Guide to the John S. Bradway Papers, 1914-1991 UA.29.02.0004
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John S. Bradway papers
1914-1991
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bradway, John Saeger
UA.29.02.0004
60 Linear Feet
0.03 Gigabytes
Papers of John S. Bradway, lawyer, legal aid advocate, and educator. Bradway's primary interest and work was in the field of legal aid. He served as Secretary of the National Association of Legal Aid Organizations (NALAO) from 1922-1940, and as its President from 1940-1942. While at Duke University, Bradway founded and directed the Duke Legal Aid Clinic from 1931 until 1959. The bulk of the collection reflects Bradway's role as Secretary for the National Association of Legal Aid Organizations (NALAO). Some materials were gathered by John Lindsey, a colleague and friend of Bradway's, and include writings, teaching materials, and some correspondence. Materials include correspondence with various state and city legal aid bureaus, detailed statistics and annual reports from these organizations, correspondence with various national social service and aid agencies such as the National Conference on Social Work, and NALAO committee reports and conference proceedings. Also included are chapter files of his books, addresses, and articles written by Bradway on topics relating to legal aid.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
John S. Bradway was born Feb. 17, 1890 in Swarthmore, Pennsylvania to William and Jennie S. Bradway. He graduated from Haverford College with an A.B. in 1911 and an A.M. in 1915. He received his law degree from University of Pennsylvania in 1914 and received an honorary law degree from Haverford in 1957. Bradway began his academic teaching career at the University of Pennsylvania where he taught in the Sociology Department from 1927 to 1928. At the same time, he taught at the Pennsylvania School of Social and Health Work (1927-1929). In 1929 he moved to California and began a short career at the University of Southern California Law School (1929-1931). Bradway moved to Durham in 1931 where he taught law at Duke from 1931 to 1959. After leaving Durham, Bradway taught at the Hastings College of Law in San Francisco and at California Western University until his retirement in 1970. Bradway was married to Mary Henderson in 1921. He died on January 2, 1985 in Eureka, California.
Bradway's primary interest and work was in the field of legal aid. He served as Secretary of the National Association of Legal Aid Organizations (NALAO) from 1922-1940, and as its President from 1940-1942. While at Duke, Bradway founded and directed the Duke Legal Aid Clinic from 1931 until 1959. The purpose of the Clinic was to provide practical training for law students. They participated in practical activities such as conferring with clients, gaining interview skills, and preparing a real case for trial. Students acquired skills in legal writing through the preparation of trial briefs and legal memoranda. The Clinic served clients who were unable to pay counsel fees, most often the indigent, immigrants, minorities, and servicemen. In addition to Bradway, the Clinic had a staff of five members of the North Carolina State Bar who assisted in educational and supervisory activities, as well as representing the Clinic's clients in court. Bradway lobbied throughout his career for law schools to make a commitment for student training through legal aid clinics.
Bradway's service to the legal aid community was extensive. He chaired the legal aid committees of the Pennsylvania and North Carolina Bar Associations, as well as the Legal Aid Clinics Committee of the Association of American Law Schools. He was also an active member of the National Conference of Social Work, the American Association of Social Workers, the International Bar Association, and served as chair of the Research Committee for the Interprofessional Commission on Marriage and Divorce Laws.
His dedication to social service and legal aid extended to state and local organizations. He served as president of the North Carolina Conference for Social Service, North Carolina Mental Hygiene Society, State Legislative Council, and as director of the North Carolina League for Crippled Children. In Durham, Bradway was president of the Durham Council of Social Agencies, Family Service Agency, Rotary Club, and the Crime Study Club. He was a member of the Advisory Board of the Durham Child Guidance Clinic, Salvation Army Home and Hospital, YWCA, and Community Chest. In addition, he was chair of a committee appointed by the Durham City Council to establish a Juvenile Court in 1933, and of a committee appointed to study sub-standard housing in 1948.
Bradway wrote extensively on the topic of legal aid. His publications include: How To Organize a Legal Aid Clinic (1931); Forms of Legal Aid Organizations (1940); Duke University Legal Aid Clinic Handbook (1954); The History of a Lawsuit (1958); How to Practice Law Effectively (1958).
Provenance
The John S. Bradway Papers were received by the Duke University Archives as a transfer in 1962 and 1973, and as a gift in 2017.
Collection Overview
The bulk of the collection reflects the work of John S. Bradway in his role as Secretary for the National Association of Legal Aid Organizations (NALAO). Materials include correspondence with various state and city legal aid bureaus, detailed statistics and annual reports from these organizations, correspondence with various national social service and aid agencies such as the National Conference on Social Work, and NALAO committee reports and conference proceedings. Also included are chapter files of his books, addresses, and articles written by Bradway on topics relating to legal aid. Duke Legal Aid Clinic (DLAC) materials are also present.
Bound volumes include correspondence, pamphlets, reports, and other materials related to John Bradway's work with NALAO which have been bound together into volumes. These series of volumes were numbered, and are incomplete.
Accession UA2017.0063 was gathered by John M. Lindsey, a friend and colleague of John Bradway, and includes copies of writings and teaching materials created by Bradway, as well as some correspondence and materials related to Bradway's death.
Conservation note
Bound volumes were scheduled for disbinding in 2014; Z Volumes 12, 21, 30, 31, 35, 37, 38, 39, 40, and 45 were disbound by Conservation and placed in Hollinger boxes, before determining the process was too intensive for condition and anticipated use. During re-processing for accurate description and box numbers, TS Archivist Tracy Jackson determined some volumes (not yet reviewed by Conservation) would be in need of conservation treatment and disbinding in order to withstand use. After consulting with TS Head Kat Stefko, University Archivist Val Gillespie, and Conservator Erin Hammeke, those volumes identified as being in poor condition would be boxed separately and marked for Conservation treatment after use. These volumes were:
Conditions Governing Access
Access copies of electronic records must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
Lawyers -- United States; Legal Aid -- United States; National Association of Legal Aid Organizations; Duke University. Legal Aid Clinic; Duke University. School of Law
- Papers, 1914-1949; 1
  - Receipts, Dues, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
  - Receipts, Dues, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Requests, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
  - Requests, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Telegrams, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Organizations, 1940 November (Box 1)
  - Re: Statistics, 1940 February-April (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Legal Aid Society, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
  - Los Angeles Legal Aid Clinic, 1929-1932 (Box 1)
  - Los Angeles, California, 1930-1931 (Box 1)
  - Los Angeles, California, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - Berkeley, California, 1930-1933 (Box 1)
  - Little Rock, Arkansas, 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - Toronto, Canada, 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - Montreal, P.Q., 1930-1933 (Box 1)
  - Toronto, Canada, 1929-1933 (Box 1)
  - Montreal, Canada, 1923-1924 (Box 1)
  - Alberta, Canada, 1929 July-August (Box 1)
  - Winnipeg, Canada, 1924-1932 (Box 1)
  - Denver, Colorado, 1930-1933 (Box 1)
  - Denver Legal Aid Society, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - San Diego, California, 1929-1933 (Box 1)
  - Southern California Legal Claims, 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - California, General, 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - General Files, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
  - Alabama, 1926-1932 (Box 1)
  - Arizona, 1931, January-May (Box 1)
  - Oakland, California, 1923-1933 (Box 1)
  - San Francisco, Los Angeles, California, 1929-1933 (Box 1)
  - Oakland, Los Angeles, 1930-1931 (Box 1)
  - National Conference on Family Relations, 1947, May (Box 1)
  - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania - Ottinger, William M., 1929-1933 (Box 2)
  - American Association of Social Workers, 1935, April-May (Box 2)
  - National Conference of Social Work, 1934-1935; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Organizations, 1928-1931 (Box 2)
  - Unfoldered, 1937 July-September; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Unfoldered Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Unfoldered, 1938 July (Box 2)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Offices 1938 Conference, 1938 May-October (Box 2)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Offices 1938 Conference, 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Offices 1938 Conference, 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - New Haven, Connecticut, 1932-1933 (Box 2)
  - Legal Aid Committee, Bridgeport Connecticut, 1923-1933 (Box 2)
  - Contributions, 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - New Haven, Connecticut, 1922-1932 (Box 2)
  - Yale Law School, 1924-1929 (Box 2)
  - Connecticut, 1930, 1922-1932 (Box 2)
  - Wilmington, Delaware, 1925 May-October (Box 2)
  - Legal Aid Society, Washington DC, 1932-1933 (Box 2)
  - American Association of Personal Finance Companies, 1932 July-December (Box 2)
  - Hartford Connecticut, 1923-1933 (Box 2)
  - American Association of Personal Finance Companies, 1931-1933 (Box 2)
  - Washington D.C., 1930 (Box 2)
  - U.S. Children's Bureau, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
  - National Association Convention, Montreal, 1938 October-December (Box 3)
  - Director's, Officers of Various Legal Aid Services, Undated (Box 3)
  - Washington D.C., 1931-1933 (Box 3)
  - Tweed-Bradway Correspondence, 1938 April-June (Box 3)
  - Amendment to N.Y. Constitution, 1938 May-June (Box 3)
  - Hackney Questionnaire, 1938 March-April (Box 3)
  - "Lance of Justice" Requests, 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Henry C. Hart, 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Inquiries, 1938-1939 (Box 3)
  - Inquiries, 1937-1938; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Inquiry, 1925 (Box 3)
  - Lexington, Kentucky, 1924-1929 (Box 3)
  - Kentucky General File, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Louisiana, 1927-1932 (Box 3)
  - U.S. Children's Bureau, Miss Lenroot, Martha Wood, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
  - U.S. Children's Bureau, Katherine Lenroot, 1930-1932 (Box 3)
  - Louisville, Kentucky, 1930-1933 (Box 3)
  - Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada, 1923 March-November (Box 3)
  - Portland, Maine, 1923-1930 (Box 3)
  - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1930-1933 (Box 3)
  - Louisiana, 1929-1930 (Box 3)
  - American National Red Cross, 1928 May-October (Box 3)
  - Study of Legal Aid in the South, 1929 April-August (Box 3)
  - Membership Applications, 1937 (Box 3)
  - Membership Applications, 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Organizations Committee Reports, 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Florida, 1924-1932 (Box 3)
  - Detailed Statistics, 1934; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Mrs. Starkey's Questionnaire, 1938-1940 (Box 4)
  - Replies from Executive Committee, 1939-1940 (Box 4)
  - American Association of Schools of Social Work, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - Legal Aid Committee, American Bar Association, 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - Committee on Publicity and Finance, 1934-1935 (Box 4)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Organizations Committee Reports, 1934-1935 (Box 4)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Organizations Executive Committee, Officer's Letters of Appointment, 1934 November (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Grace P. Maness, 1934 June-August (Box 4)
  - How to Organize a Legal Aid Organization (Plans), 1933-1934 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence with Grace P. Maness, 1935 June-August (Box 4)
  - National Social Work Committee, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - National Conference of Social Work, 1937 March-June (Box 4)
  - National Conference of Social Work, 1937 January-March (Box 4)
  - National Conference of Social Work, 1936 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Law Schools, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - American Association of Social Workers, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - Family Welfare Association, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - Foreign Language Information Service, 1937 April-May (Box 4)
  - Committee on Publicity and Finance, 1936 April-June (Box 4)
  - Louisville Convention Matters, 1935 October-November (Box 4)
  - Gardiner Nominating Committee, 1937 September-October (Box 4)
  - Correspondence with Marguerite Gariepy, Nellie MacNamara, Grace Maness, 1937 August-September (Box 4)
  - Claude E. Clarke, 1937 January-July (Box 4)
  - Committee on Relations with Law Schools, 1937 January-June (Box 4)
  - Miss Ruth Miner, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - Public Administration Service, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - Trips, 1937 January-June (Box 4)
  - Convention Suggestions, 1935 September-October (Box 4)
  - Convention Suggestions, 1935 January-September (Box 4)
  - Convention, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
  - Article "Today", 1934-1935 (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association, 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association Legal Aid Committee, 1937 (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania, 1936-1938 (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association, 1938 March-April (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association, 1938 February-March (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association, 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association, 1937 September-November (Box 5)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Organizations Conference, 1936-1937 (Box 5)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Organizations, 1937 September-October (Box 5)
  - Form Letters, 1937 February-June (Box 5)
  - Form Letters, 1937 January-February (Box 5)
  - Form Letters, 1936-1937 (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association, 1936 December (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania Bar, Legal Aid Committee, 1937 January-March (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association Legal Aid Committee, 1937 February-April (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association Legal Aid Committee, 1937 January-May (Box 5)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association Legal Aid Committee, 1937 March-September (Box 5)
  - "How to Organize" Legal Aid Organizations, Chapter, 1933-1934 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, How to Organize Legal Aid Organizations, 1934 (Box 6)
  - How to Organize Legal Aid Organizations Chapter II, 1934 May-July (Box 6)
  - How to Organize a Legal Aid Organization Chapters, 1933-1934 (Box 6)
  - Detailed Statistics, 1931-1932 (Box 6)
  - National Defense, National Association of Legal Aid Organizations, 1941 January-July (Box 6)
  - Legal Service for the Indigent, 1941 February-March (Box 6)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Organizations, 1945 May-September (Box 6)
  - Inquiries, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
  - Inquiries, 1937 February-April (Box 6)
  - National Association of Legal Aid Organizations Correspondence, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Report of the Legal Aid Committee of the PA Bar Association, 1941 February-April (Box 6)
  - Legal Aid Committee of State Bar Associations, 1940-1941 (Box 6)
  - Harrison Tweed, 1945 March-October (Box 6)
  - Vernon Marr, Treasury Matters, etc., 1940-1941 (Box 6)
  - Legal Aid Committee of the Pennsylvania Bar Association, 1940-1941 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 6)
  - Final Draft, Chapter VIII, circa 1934 (Box 6)
  - Chapter VII, 1934 May-October (Box 6)
  - "The Organization of a Legal Aid Bureau," Chapter V, 1927-1935 (Box 6)
  - "The Organization of a Legal Aid Bureau," Chapter VII, circa 1934 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, Last Name "R", 1945 May-November (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, Last Name "S", 1945 May-December (Box 6)
  - "The Organization of Legal Aid Bureaus," Chapter VIII, 1935 January (Box 6)
  - State Legislative Council, 1945 May (Box 6)
  - Supply Lists, etc., 1945 (Box 6)
  - Telegrams not Relating to Cases, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, Last Name "O", 1945 July-November (Box 6)
  - National Conference of Social Work, 1945 July-October (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, Last Name, "P", 1945 July-November (Box 6)
  - National Conference on Family Relations, 1945 September-December (Box 6)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association, Committee on War Work, 1944-1945 (Box 6)
  - Legal Aid Progress, 1936-1937 (Box 6)
  - Forms of Legal Aid Organization in Middle-sized Cities and Smaller Communities, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Nashville Convention, Letters and Correspondence, 1940 October (Box 7)
  - Detailed Statistics, 1934-1936 (Box 7)
  - Small Claims Courts, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Specified Types of Cases, 1939-1940; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Trips, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
  - Personal Letters, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - State Conference of Social Life, 1940 April-October (Box 7)
  - State, Local Bar Committee, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
  - Legal Aid Sections of State Welfare Conferences, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Law and Social Work; National Conference on Social Work, 1941 January-June (Box 7)
  - Newsletter Suggestions Sent to Enemy Brownell, 1941 February-May (Box 7)
  - New Legal Aid Organizations, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Receipts, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Social Work and the Law, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Public Administration Service, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
  - Informa Pauperis, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Association, National Defense Activities, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Russell Sage Grant, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Legal Aid Newsletter, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Misc. Reports, etc., 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Requests, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Sectional Meeting, 1941 May (Box 7)
  - Committee on Publicity, Clephane, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
  - Reginald H. Smith, Re: Legal Aid Work and Social Work, 1941 May-June (Box 7)
  - Surveys, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - A Tentative Bibliography on Legal Aid, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with Mr. Boyce Concerning Jacksonville Program, 1940 January-November (Box 7)
  - Minimum Statistics, 1939 (Box 8)
  - Minimum Statistics, 1939 (Box 8)
  - Family Welfare Association, 1940 January-March (Box 8)
  - Legal Aid Records and Standards, 1940 October (Box 8)
  - American Association of Personal Finance, 1939-1940 (Box 8)
  - National Conference of Social Work, 1939-1940 (Box 8)
  - Junior Bar Conference, 1939-1940 (Box 8)
  - National Social Work Council, 1939-1940 (Box 8)
  - Community Chest Matters, 1939 (Box 8)
  - American Bar Association, 1940 (Box 8)
  - American Bar Association, 1939 September-December (Box 8)
  - American Bar Association, 1939 July-October (Box 8)
  - Inter-American Bar Association, 1940-1941 (Box 8)
  - Interpreter Release, 1940-1941 (Box 8)
  - International Organization of Industrial Accident Boards and Commissions, 1939 (Box 8)
  - Baltimore Legal Aid Bureau, 1935-1936 (Box 8)
  - Maryland, General, 1935-1936 (Box 8)
  - Chapter VI, circa 1934 (Box 8)
  - Chapter III, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Chapter VI, circa 1934 (Box 8)
  - Nominating Committee NALAO, 1941 January-March (Box 8)
  - Committee on Relations with Social Agencies, NALAO, 1941 January-April (Box 8)
  - Committee on Relations with Other Agencies, 1940-1941 (Box 8)
  - Time and Place Committee, NALAO, 1941 February (Box 8)
  - Correspondence re: Secretary's Material Sent to E. Brownell, Financial Transactions, Routine Matters, etc., 1941 February-March (Box 8)
  - Audit Report, Financial Reports, 1940-1941 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, "How to Organize a Legal Aid Society", 1934 June-September (Box 8)
  - How to Organize, Notes and Research, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Bulletin #124: Speeches Delivered at the N.Y. State Conference on Social Work (Box 9)
  - Baltimore Conference, 1941 January-July (Box 9)
  - National Conference of Social Work, 1940-1941 (Box 9)
  - National Conference of Social Work, Atlantic City Meeting, 1941, April-May (Box 9)
  - Answers to Request for Suggestions for Improvement of Annual Conferences, 1940, November (Box 9)
  - Applications for Membership and New Members, 1941 January-May (Box 9)
  - American Bar Association, 1940-1941 (Box 9)
  - The Annals, 1940 September-November (Box 9)
  - Alien Registration, 1940 September-December (Box 9)
  - New Jersey, General, 1939-1940 (Box 9)
  - Reginald H. Smith, 1938-1939 (Box 9)
  - New Mexico, 1939 August (Box 9)
  - New Jersey, General, 1935-1936 (Box 9)
  - Newark, New Jersey, 1935 September (Box 9)
  - Missouri, General, 1935-1936 (Box 9)
  - Kansas City, 1935 June-August (Box 9)
  - St. Paul Legal Aid Department, 1936 April (Box 9)
  - Minneapolis Legal Aid Society, 1935-1936 (Box 9)
  - Michigan, General, 1935-1936 (Box 9)
  - Grand Rapids Legal Aid Bureau, 1935 August (Box 9)
  - Detroit Legal Aid Bureau, 1936 January-May (Box 9)
  - Massachusetts General, 1935-1936 (Box 9)
  - Cambridge, Harvard Legal Aid Bureau, 1935-1936 (Box 9)
  - Reginald Heber Smith, 1935-1936 (Box 9)
  - Boston Legal Aid Society, 1935-1936 (Box 9)
  - New Jersey, General, 1936-1937 (Box 9)
  - Missouri, General, 1936-1937 (Box 9)
  - St. Louis Legal Aid Bureau, 1936-1937 (Box 9)
  - St. Paul Legal Aid Bureau, 1936-1937 (Box 9)
  - Duluth Legal Aid Bureau, 1937 May (Box 9)
  - Michigan, General, 1936 August-September (Box 9)
  - Grand Rapids Legal Aid Bureau, 1936 (Box 9)
  - Detroit Legal Aid Bureau, 1936-1937 (Box 9)
  - Massachusetts, General, 1936 October-November (Box 9)
  - New Bedford, Massachusetts, 1936-1937 (Box 9)
  - Boston Legal Aid Society, 1936-1937 (Box 9)
  - Reginald H Smith, 1936-1937 (Box 9)
  - Cambridge, Harvard Legal Aid Bureau, 1937 April (Box 9)
  - New Orleans Legal Aid Bureau, 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - New Jersey, General, 1937-1938 (Box 9)
  - Public Defenders, 1930-1940 (Box 9)
  - Bibliography, circa 1940 (Box 9)
  - Nominating Committee, 1939-1940 (Box 9)
  - Committee on Internal Administration, Gardiner, 1939-1940 (Box 9)
  - Committee on Internal Administration, Gardiner, 1939 November (Box 9)
  - Committee Chairman, 1940 November (Box 9)
  - Committee on Women's Compensation, Joseph Bear, 1939-1940 (Box 9)
  - Committee on Finance, Edmund Beckwith, 1939-1940 (Box 9)
  - Clephane, Chairman, Special Committee to Contact Attorney General Jackson, 1940 April-August (Box 9)
  - National Defense Program, 1940 May-December (Box 9)
  - Committee on Relations with Other Agencies, Harris, 1939-1940 (Box 9)
  - Community Chest Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 10)
  - Emery Brownell, 1941 April-July (Box 10)
  - Community Chest Correspondence, 1940 October-December (Box 10)
  - Communications to Executive Committee from Secretary, 1940-1941 (Box 10)
  - Committee on Approaching Foundations, 1941 January-June (Box 10)
  - Correspondence with the Executive Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 10)
  - Letters to Membership on Subject of Finance and Promotion Committee, and Some Answers, 1940 November (Box 10)
  - Executive Committee Meeting in New York, 1940-1941 (Box 10)
  - Committee on Finances, 1940-1941 (Box 10)
  - Subcommittee on Finance and Promotion, 1941 June-July (Box 10)
  - Promotion, Inquiries, Etc., 1941 April-June (Box 10)
  - Committee on Constitutional Status of Membership Dues and Correspondence Re: Increasing Membership Dues, 1941 March-July (Box 10)
  - Public Administration Service, 1938-1939 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Committee Appointments, 1940 November-December (Box 10)
  - National Conference Social Work, 1938-1939 (Box 10)
  - Community Chest Correspondence, 1940 October (Box 10)
  - Community Chest Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets, Reports, Correspondence, 1948-1949; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, "How to Organize", 1931-1934 (Box 10)
  - "How to Organize" Chapter II, 1934 (Box 10)